compassionuk.org 2017-10-09

# Cookies & privacy - How we store your data- Compassion UK

### Information Collected Through The Compassion UK website

Some personal data is collected through the site when you voluntarily choose to provide us with personal data.

When you create a myCompassion account on this website we will ask you for your name, email address and postcode so that we can connect your account with your sponsored child. This enables you to send letters and gifts online.

Any forms that you decide to fill on the website (e.g. applying to become a Compassion Volunteer) will be kept strictly confidential and will adhere to our policy on sharing and using collected information below.

### Sharing and Usage on Collected Information

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

### Use of Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit.

To learn more about cookies, you can visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/). You will also find details on how to block and delete cookies from your computer as well as more general information about cookies. For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile phone you will need to refer to your handset manual.

### The Cookies We Use:

**Log-in to myCompassion** – We place a cookie on your computer when you log-in to myCompassion, to save you logging in in future.  This cookie is removed when you log out of myCompassion.

**Suppress the cookie notice** – the first time you load the Compassion UK homepage, you will see a notice at top of the page about cookies.  We place a cookie on your computer when you press X, so that you don’t see this notice in future.

**Google Analytics** – These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website and help us to continually improve our blog. For instance, which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous.

This data helps us to understand:

  * Which pages people visit on the site
  * Which internet browsers are being used
  * What is popular on the site
  * Which interactive tools are used by visitors

You can find out more about Google’s cookies on their privacy policy: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/> You can also install the Google Analytics Opt-out tools in your browser: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.

### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on the this webpage.

### External Links

Compassion UK is not responsible for the availability or content of external sites that may be linked to, from the site. If you find a broken link or if you have any questions or concerns about a link, please [contact us](http://www.compassionuk.org/contact).
